Frederick K. Articuno

Phone - (804) 704-0334 | Email - mckiyoshi@gmail.com | Location - Colonial Heights, Va 23834 | Github - github.com/fkarticuno | LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/frederick-articuno | Portfolio - fkarticuno.github.io/CodingPortfolio

Summary

Full-Stack *MERN* Web Developer leveraging experience in numerous frameworks and languages. Known as a curious mind with a continuous focus on the next steps and perpetual improvement. With each project, the goal is to use current knowledge to develop a stable platform from which to expand from the minimum viable product into the frontiers of technology. Excited to leverage skills in the future as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team in order to build better experiences on the web and develop more concise code for the future.

Technical Skills

MongoDB | Express.js | React.js | Node.js | CSS | HTML | Firebase | Git | CSS | Bootstrap | JavaScript | JQuery | Timers | Ajax | MySQL | Handlebars | Sequelize | API Integration | Heroku | User Authorization | Java | Microsoft Office | Google Suite | IBM TN73270

Projects

<u>UoR Full Stack Coding Certification Course</u>; Richmond, Virginia Coding Portfolio

07/2019 - 02/2020

https://fkarticuno.github.io/CodingPortfolio/https://github.com/fkarticuno/CodingPortfolio/

Portfolio displaying progress and achievements developing basic, intermediate and advanced apps using various languages, packages, frameworks, engines and database models. All culminating into a demo friendly environment to showcase the expertise gained through countless hours of development and refactoring.

Uses: HTML CSS Bootstrap JavaScript JQuery GitHub-Pages

Work Experience

<u>Virginia Employment Commission</u>; Henrico, Virginia *Production Support Technician*

11/2020 -00/0000

Transcripted, corrected, and distributed dictations from pulling recorded hearings all the way to sending the completed letters to benefit recipients in support of the VEC's Office of First Level Appeals, while focusing on development and implementation of process improvements.

- Produced over 1000 transcripts with less than 10% errors.
- Created a macro within the TN3270 emulator with over 180 branching outcomes to streamline transcripting with > 95% user satisfaction. This program reduced user inputs by > 80%, converting hours of redundant actions directly into productivity.

Capital One; Chester, Virginia

08/2015 - 05/2019

Sr. Risk coordinator (02/2017 – 05/2019)

Managed inbound and outbound collection calls while performing account level research, updating account information, and completing appropriate documentation to ensure accurate reporting.

- Became a Google Guide to assist in transitioning from Microsoft Office Suite to Google Suite.
- Created Cure Estimator app to project cost analysis for customers, Awarded Spot Award.

Risk coordinator (02/2016 – 02/2017)

Maintained compliance by adhering to all Federal, State and Capital One Regulations while balancing business intent and our customer's needs to design creative solutions that make our customers lives better and show advocacy to our customers.

- Received 4 ROAR awards for performing at top 5%.
- Overcame objections that customers have about making payments toward their account(s) and help them to understand their account(s) and responsibilities.

Sr. Risk representative (08/2015 – 02/2016)

Help customers build and retain strong credit standing.

- Boosted customer engagement by helping clients build and retain a strong credit standing.
- Helped Capital One maintain our customers for life by providing exceptional call quality on every call, building on Capital One's brand through great customer service.

AmeriCorps; Petersburg, Virginia

08/2012 - 05/2013

Volunteer

Provided Plumbing services to include installation and maintenance on fountains, sinks, showers, tubs, gas and electric heating / cooling, potable water source routing, gray water/sewer water drainage along with landscaping, technological up training, roofing, painting, and bioswale installation.

• Obtained CPR, First Aid, AED, ServeSafe, LEED, OSHA and Forklift Operations certifications.

United States Marine Corps; Virginia Beach, Virginia

08/2009 - 08/2017

Data Link Coordinator - E5 Sergeant

• Completed MAJIC (Multi-tactical-data-link Advanced Joint Interoperability Course)

System Configuration Coordinator - E4 Corporal

• Sourced and maintained interoperability equipment. Awarded Promotion to E5.

Tactical Air Traffic Controller - E4 Corporal

• Managed Air traffic in/out of designated AORs. Completed operations training.

Assistant Controller - E3 - Lance Corporal

• Completed JTIDS (Joint Tactical Information Distribution Systems). Awarded Promotion to E4.

Surveillance Operator - E2 PFC

Acquired Secret Clearance. Awarded promotion to E3.

Education

University Of Richmond | Capital One Tech College | John Tyler Community College

Marine Corps Air Ground Combat Center | Tidewater Community College